# Clay Kuo

C: 267-213-2114 <u>claykuo209@gmail.com</u>

Media, PA, 19063

# **Biography**

Clay is a statistical programmer located in Pennsylvania. He recently completed the second Master degree of Applied Statistics at West Chester University in May 2024. He joined Tigermed Consulting in Apr 2020 as a statistical analyst. He was involved in multiple studies and served as a lead programmer, mainly provided services in real word data analysis, as well as generating analysis datasets, standard clinical outputs. Prior to that, he worked as a Data Management Specialist at T-TOP Clinical Research Co.Ltd from 2019 to 2020 in developing and validating analysis datasets, and summary outputs. He started as a statistical programmer intern at Talentech Consulting in Jan 2018, mainly supported generation and validation of datasets and clinical outputs.

# **Professional Experience**

## Jan 2023 - May 2024 West Chester University, West Chester, PA

Research Assistant/ Student Worker

- Performed data cleaning (issue detect and query) and data transfer.
- Provided ready-access data for the faculty and/or supervisor.
- Utilized analytical, statistical, and SAS programming skills to collect, analyze, and interpret large database.

# Apr 2020 – Jun 2022 Tigermed Consulting, Taipei, Taiwan

Statistical Analyst

- Generated and validated SDTM/ADaM datasets, table, figure and data listings (TFLs).
- Assisted in developing and reviewing programming specifications for datasets, and TFLs.
- Involved in creating standard MACRO for performing statistical summaries.
- Worked with U.S pharmaceutical companies and utilized large retrospective database experience (e.g. Optum, IQVIA, and ConcertAI) for multiple real word data projects.
- Conducted statistical analysis using Massive Healthcare Database (RWE) and relative inpatient, outpatient, prescription records.
- Function independently and worked with study team to achieve quality and on-time deliverables and meet client's expectations.

### Jun 2019 – Mar 2020 T-TOP Clinical Research Co.Ltd, Taipei, Taiwan

Biostatistics and Data Management Specialist

• Performed SAS coding in creating high-quality analysis datasets, and clinical study report related outputs (e.g. 'Central ECG', 'AE vs CM and non-drug therapy').

- Developed and validated Edit Check for data follow using Data Validation Plan.
- Generated randomization list code.
- Assisted in data cleaning (issue detect and query) and data transfer.
- Provided review comments for Statistical Analysis Plans/TFL shell as per statistical programmer perspective.

#### Jan 2018 - Jun 2019 Talentech Consulting LLC, Monmouth Junction, NJ

Statistical Programmer Intern/ Statistical Programmer

- Learned SDTM and ADaM implementation Guide.
- Understood Protocols, Statistical Analysis Plans, Specification, TLF shell and other study related documentation.
- Assisted with updating and programming datasets, tables, listings, and figures by referring to existing macros and codes.
- Under supervision, provided quality control of outputs.

### **Education**

### May 2024 West Chester University, West Chester, PA

Masters – Applied Statistics

## Nov 2017 Louisiana Tech University, Ruston, LA

Masters – Chemical Engineering

#### Jun 2013 Chung Yuan Christian University, Taoyuan, Taiwan

Bachelor – Chemical Engineering

#### Skills

- SAS/BASE, SAS/STAT, SAS/GRAPH, SAS/MACRO, SAS/SQL
- R, R Shiny
- Teradata (SQL), Tableau, Python.

### **Certificates**

- SAS Base Certification (Issued Date Oct 2017) (Certificate No: BP074629v9)
- SAS Advance Certification (Issued Date Nov 2017) (Certificate No: AP022254v9)
- Managing Big Data with MySQL Certification (Coursera Certificate No: AUFS6WHCJM2M)
- Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau (Coursera Certificate No: U64RXBPLTNNJ)
- Georgia Institute of Technology CS1301xI: Computing in Python I: Fundamentals and Procedural Programming (Certificate No: fe80bc344ac14e5cb26708a9d9dcedf1)